917.225.7503 • chris@moodydigital.com • Cary, NC 27519

INTRODUCTION

Chris is a software engineer with over 20 years of experience and a passion for interactive development. He excels at building modular components, web applications and data visualizations. Possessing a diverse skill set, he is able to fulfill the roles of tech lead, manager, individual contributor, and mentor. Chris enjoys a good challenge, and seeks opportunities that allow him to push limits, set trends, and break molds.

EDUCATION

CARNEGIE MELLON UNIVERSITY, Pittsburgh, PA

Bachelor of Science, Electrical and Computer Engineering, December 2007

SKILLS & PROFICIENCIES

Technologies
Frameworks/Libs
Tools
Deliverables
JavaScript, Typescript, SSR, sass, PostgreSQL, AWS Lambda, DynamoDB, indexedDB, C#, ES5, AS3
React, redux, Next.js, MUI, node, d3, GSAP, Highcharts, AG Grid, three.js, Vue, Dexie, pixi, jest
VSCode, copilot, git, webpack, Vite, Miro, Jira, Confluence, Figma, XD, Canva, Photoshop
Websites, MicroFrontends, apps, presentations, convention panels, games, ads, banners

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Moody's Corporation, New York, NY Staff Software Engineer, 05/2021-Present; Remote off-site

- Develop full stack features involving database queries, serverless functions and data visualization
- Increase customer engagement with the new moodys.com homepage launch
- Launch new Company Pages product and support coverage expansion initiatives to include unrated and sovereign entities
- Work with team members and participate in cross-product team efforts to create services and widgets
- Optimize project integration of our in-house shared component nanofrontend
- Foster an open and collaborative environment by encouraging curiosity around the unknown, and discussion around challenges

NeON, an FCB Health Company, New York, NY Freelance Senior Developer, 11/2013-05/2021, Remote off-site

- Develop responsive websites using various technologies such as Angular, React, Next.js, handlebars, pug
- Develop web and flash content for tablet-based CRM tools, games, banner advertisements and panels
- Develop NodeJS/Electron-based desktop servers for multi-screen, networked application rollouts
- Create data visualizations with d3. Tabulate data with AG Grid
- Attend conferences and events to provide on-site support and live updates when necessary
- Coach/Mentor team members on patterns, best practices and style
- Ensure that creative concepts stay within operable technical specs. Advise creative on user interface and experience

Hidden Level Games LLC, New York, NY Co-founder and Engineer, 10/2011-12/2017

- Develop an interactive programming game (Beta) for Desktop Windows and Mac OS in AS3 and Adobe AIR
- Create a scripting language (CodePop) that allows users to modify world and object properties
- Develop a Python web server that allows users to save and share their creations
- Program engaging gameplay mechanics; grappling hook, collect items, projectiles
- Expand CodePop with conditional and loop statements and an event system
- Create a prototype web socket server for real-time multiplayer and collaboration
- Partner with the Anita Borg foundation and similar organizations to host Beta coding camps
- Work with educators to create classroom curricula and content

Harrison and Star, New York, NY Freelance Senior Interactive Developer, 11/2011-12/2013, Remote off-site

- Develop HTML/CSS3/JavaScript content for iPad-based marketing tools
- Develop and optimize AIR applications targeting touchscreen desktop and iOS platforms
- Interface with hardware via bluetooth, usb, and serial port i/O streams
- Build a suite of applications that enable iPads to control video content across networked devices using web sockets
- Create particle effects and three dimensional experiences with WebGL
- Architect a SQLite database manager for tracking, storing and distributing application metrics
- Contribute technical expertise to the creative process, vetting ideas against specifications and timelines
- Develop HTML/JavaScript websites with backwards-compatibility all the way down to IE7

Tremor Video, New York, NY Freelance Senior Developer, 08/2011-11/2011

- Develop and optimize video and rich media banner advertisements
- Guide and mentor junior developers on best practices and style

NeON, an FCB Health Company, New York, NY Freelance Senior Developer, 06/2010-04/2011

- Architect a content development framework for direct sales solution platforms. Target web, DVD/CD, Exploria, and Skura
- Write and generate documentation with ASDoc
- Mentor and train developers on process, best practices and framework
- Distribute tasks to team members based on skill level. Interview and evaluate new candidates
- Develop and optimize banners, microsites and rich media apps for Pfizer, Boehringer-Ingelheim, and others
- Provide technical guidance to the creative team. Ensure that concepts stay within operable technical specs

Visual Alchemy, New York, NY Freelance Front-End Developer, 04/2010-06/2010

- Build a variety of modular flash applications for web, desktop and DVD release
- Stream online video via Flash Media Server, and package offline apps with both Zinc and AIR
- Build HTML/CSS/JavaScript websites from Photoshop comps
- Assist creative team during brainstorming, pitch & design phases. Ensure that concepts stay within operable technical specs

FCB Health, New York, NY Freelance Senior Developer, 02/2010-04/2010

- Build and animate interactive widgets and charts
- Mentor and train developers on process and framework
- Distribute tasks to team members. Interview and evaluate new candidates.

LLNS, New York, NY Lead Developer, 08/2009-01/2010

- Architect a scalable content development framework for direct sales solution platforms
- Distribute tasks to team members based on skill level. Interview and evaluate new candidates
- Set the tone for development by introducing key Object-Oriented programming practices
- Work with design, account teams, and tech directors to keep projects on track and within spec

Erkel Associates, Crozet, VA Independent Consultant, 02/2009-08/2009, Remote off-site

- Develop various interactive kiosk applications leveraging Actionscript 3 and Intuit touchscreen framework
- Allow several customization options via an XML-based content management system

IBM, Research Triangle Park, NC Engineer/Scientist, 01/2008-03/2009

- Write Actionscript 3 test applications used to determine the stability of hardware components
- Identify, track, and solve defects blocking critical test cycles

IBM, Research Triangle Park, NC Pre-Professional Co-op Engineer, May-August(annually 2004-2007)

- Completed four consecutive summer internships
- Develop practical test tools and applications using Flash and Actionscript 2/3
- Perform various tasks in the areas of schematic design, signal integrity, component testing, and networking